Guide to the Whitelaw Reid Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Whitelaw Reid papers
1865-1923
MS 1458
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8
(11 boxes and 1 folio)
The papers consist of nine volumes of autographed letters written by prominent American, British, and French political, financial, literary, and cultural figures. The majority of letters are addressed to Whitelaw Reid or Elizabeth Mills Reid, and date from Reid's service as ambassador to Great Britain. Letters of introduction, acknowledgements of gifts and invitations, congratulatory messages, and letters of condolence comprise the bulk of the letters. The volumes also include letters relating to the New York Tribune and substantive letters from President Theodore Roosevelt (1906-1907) concerning Morocco, the Algeciras Conference, and other diplomatic and political matters.
Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ogden Reid, 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
The papers are available on microfilm (2,015 frames on 2 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM 169.
Associated Materials
Associated material: Whitelaw Reid Papers, Library of Congress.
Biographical / Historical
Whitelaw Reid was born near Xenia, Ohio on October 27, 1837. He worked as a journalist during the Civil War and in 1868 joined the New York Tribune. He assumed control of the paper in 1872 and married Elizabeth Mills in 1881. Reid was active in Republican Party politics and served as Benjamin Harrison's ambassador to France (1889-1892). He ran for vice-president in 1892, and served as a member of the commission to negotiate a treaty with Spain following the Spanish American War. Reid also served as United States ambassador to Great Britain (1905-1912). He died on December 15, 1912.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of nine volumes of autographed letters written by prominent American, British, and French political, financial, literary, and cultural figures. The majority of letters are addressed to Whitelaw Reid or Elizabeth Mills Reid, and date from Reid's service as ambassador to Great Britain. Letters of introduction, acknowledgements of gifts and invitations, congratulatory messages, and letters of condolence comprise the bulk of the letters. The volumes also include letters relating to the New York Tribune and substantive letters from President Theodore Roosevelt (1906-1907) concerning Morocco, the Algeciras Conference, and other diplomatic and political matters.
Arrangement
Original volumes are arranged in numerical order (I-IX), with oversize material (not microfilmed) filed after the volumes. The microfilm publication and copyflow (use copies) documents are arranged in the same manner and listed last.
Conditions Governing Access
The papers have been microfilmed. Patrons must use FILM HM 169 or the printed copies produced from the microfilm (boxes 1-3) instead of the originals. The folio (box 4) was not microfilmed and patrons may use the originals.
Other Finding Aids
For an index of correspondents with Whitelaw Reid, please consult the Correspondents Index.
New York tribune; Journalism; Newspaper publishing; United States -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain; United States -- History -- 1865-1921; United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1933; Autographs; Ambassadors; Diplomats; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872; Knollys, Francis, Viscount of Caversham, 1837-1924; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; Reid, Elizabeth Mills, 1858-1931; Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Windsor, House of; International Conference on Moroccan Affairs -- Algeciras, Spain -- 1906
- Originals, 1864-1923; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The volumes in the series may not be used in the original form. Researchers are required to use FILM HM 169 or the copies (copyflo) in Series II produced from this microfilm instead of the originals. The oversize material in box 4 may be used in its original form.
  - Volume I: Correspondence with Presidents, Vice Presidents, State Governors, 1864-1921
    - Cleveland, Grover, 1883 April 25 (Box 5)
    - Garfield, James A., 1868 March 5 (Box 5)
    - Harding, Warren G., 1921 March 26 (Box 5)
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1892 December 5 (Box 5)
    - Hayes, Rutherford B., 1886 July 12 (Box 5)
    - Johnson, Andrew, 1865 May 1 (Box 5)
    - McKinley, William, 1896 March 21 (Box 5)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1885 October 17-1915 March 29 (Box 5)
    - Taft, William H., 1905 April 21-1906 May 30 (Box 5)
    - Marburg, Theodore, 1906 June 12-19 (Box 5)
    - Taft, William H., 1906 May 30-1921 July 5 (Box 5)
    - Wilson,Woodrow, 1911 October 6-1913 November 14 (Box 5)
    - Colfax, Schuyler, 1864 May 4 (Box 5)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1921 April 2-May 15 (Box 5)
    - Fairbanks, Charles W., 1908 April 10, 1913 November 8 (Box 5)
    - Hobart, Garret A., 1898 April 20 (Box 5)
    - Morton, Levi P., 1876 October 19 (Box 5)
    - Sherman, James S., 1907 February 12, 1912 March 13 (Box 5)
    - Allen, Henry J. (Kansas), 1919 November 17 (Box 5)
    - Deneen, Charles Samuel (Illinois), 1912 May 11 (Box 5)
    - Dix, John A. (New York), 1874 September 5, 1912 January 9 (Box 5)
    - Gillett, J. N. (California), 1910 April 14 (Box 5)
    - Hay, M. E. (Washington), 1911 May 19 (Box 5)
    - Kitchin, Claude (North Carolina), 1911 May 29 (Box 5)
    - McCullough, John G. (Vermont), 1910 January 11 (Box 5)
    - McGovern, Francis E. (Wisconsin), 1911 March 22 (Box 5)
    - O'Neal, Emmet (Alabama), 1911 March 28 (Box 5)
    - Quinby, Henry B. (New Hampshire), 1909 May 22 (Box 5)
    - Sheldon, George R. (Nebraska), 1907 (Box 5)
    - Stokes, E. (New Jersey), 1906 May 14 (Box 5)
    - Stubbs, W. R. (Kansas), 1909 February 9 (Box 5)
    - Warner, Fred M. (Michigan), 1908 March 16 (Box 5)
  - Volume II: Correspondence with Cabinet, Ambassadors, Consuls, Senators
    - Cabinet Members and Associates
      - Blaine, J. G., 1875 June 10 (Box 6)
      - Bryan, W. J., 1915 February 24 (Box 6)
      - Bountwell, George S., Hon., 1876 August 8 (Box 6)
      - Carlisle, John G., 1898 July 12 (Box 6)
      - Chandler, W. E., 1894 January 10, 1900 September 23 (Box 6)
      - Daugherty, H. M. (to William H. Hayes), 1921 December 2 (Box 6)
      - Denby, Edwin, 1921 June 13, November 4 (Box 6)
      - Dennison, W. (To "Gentlemen" their Excellencies the Governors of the Southern States), 1865 November 5 (Box 6)
      - Evarts, W. M., 1878 January 30 (Box 6)
      - Fish, Hamilton, 1873 December 22 (Box 6)
      - Fletcher, H. P., 1921 May 4, undated (Box 6)
      - Foster, John W., 1889 March 20, 1983 January 7 (Box 6)
      - Garfield, James Rudolph, 1906 October 19, 1914 August 19 (Box 6)
      - Garrison, L. M., 1914 November 7 (Box 6)
      - Gusham, W. Q., 1883 September 17 (Box 6)
      - Harrison, L., 1921 July 30 (Box 6)
      - Hay, John, 1905 June 3 (Box 6)
      - Hays, W. H., 1921 December 2 (Box 6)
      - Hilles, Charles D. (to W. W. Hawkins), 1911 July 24 (Box 6)
      - Knox, P. C., 1906 December 2-1910 June 6 (Box 6)
      - Lassiter, W. (to Miss Morgan), 1919 October 29 (Box 6)
      - Loomis, F. B., 1905 April 20 (Box 6)
      - McCulloch, Hugh (to the Provisional Governors of the Southern States), 1865 November 6 (Box 6)
      - MacVeagh, Franklin, 1912 November 30 (Box 6)
      - Metcalf, V. H., 1907 October 18 (Box 6)
      - Meyer, George V. L., 1912 December 31 (Box 6)
      - Moore, W. L., 1911 March 30, undated (Box 6)
      - Morton, P., Undated (July 10) (Box 6)
      - Phillips, William, 1909 May 8, 1912 December 27 (Box 6)
      - Root, Elihu, 1893 December 26-1913 January 22 (Box 6)
      - Shaw, L. M., 1906 May 30 (Box 6)
      - Sherman, John, 1879 December 21 (Box 6)
      - Stimson, Henry L., 1912 December 13 (Box 6)
      - Wadsworth, Eliot, 1921 October 1 (Box 6)
      - Weeks, J. W., 1921 November 5 (Box 6)
      - Whitney, W. C., 1885 February 28 (Box 6)
      - Wickersham, G., 1911 March 22 (Box 6)
    - Ambassadors and Consuls
      - Beaupre, A. M. (to Hon. Henry White), 1908 August 22 (Box 6)
      - Bigelow, John, 1892 June 11-1906 December 12 (Box 6)
      - Blanchard, C. Bailly, 1908 December 31 (Box 6)
      - Bryce, Lloyd, 1912 December 16 (Box 6)
      - Choate, Joseph H., 1904 August 23-1910 October 15 (Box 6)
      - Dougherty, Raymond P., 1912 October 28 (Box 6)
      - Egan, M. F., 1908 October 30 (Box 6)
      - Forbes, W. Cameron, 1911 May 26 (Box 6)
      - Francis, Charles S., 1907 July 25 (Box 6)
      - Griffith, John L., 1909 October 29 (Box 6)
      - Guild, Curtis, 1912 June 27 (Box 6)
      - Harvey, George, 1921 April 12 (Box 6)
      - Heinke, W., 1912 April 12 (Box 6)
      - Herrick, Myron T., 1915 December 21 (Box 6)
      - Hill, David J., 1909 September 22 (Box 6)
      - Hollis, W. S., 1910 July 2 (Box 6)
      - Holloway, W. R., 1898 November 5 (Box 6)
      - Jay, John, 1879 April 6 (Box 6)
      - Jay, Peter Augustus, 1905 October 30, 1906 November 15 (Box 6)
      - Lamont, F. W., 1919 April 16 (Box 6)
      - Lauchlin, T., 1911 August 12 (Box 6)
      - Lincoln, R., 1889 August 29 (Box 6)
      - McCormick, Robert S., 1906 October 22 (Box 6)
      - Mason, Frank H., 1912 December 15 (Box 6)
      - O'Brien, T. J., Undated (Box 6)
      - Page, Walter H., 1914 December 19 (Box 6)
      - Porter, Horace, 1902 January 16 (Box 6)
      - Riddle, J. W., 1909 May 5 (Box 6)
      - Sharp, W. G. (to J. R. Carter), 1916 February 28 (Box 6)
      - Straight, William, 1912 May 24 (Box 6)
      - Taft, Alphonse, 1883 July 13 (Box 6)
      - Tower, Charlemagne, 1889 June 30, 1906 June 25 (Box 6)
      - Westacott, R. (to Miss Rogers), 1910 June 4 (Box 6)
      - White, Andrew D., 1900 April 16 (Box 6)
      - White, Henry, 1908 September 12 (Box 6)
      - Whitehouse, Sheldon, Undated (Box 6)
      - Wilson, Henry Lane, 1907 June 18, 1910 July 2 (Box 6)
      - Worton, Thomas H., 1910 May 7 (Box 6)
    - Spanish Peace Commission
      - Castillo, F. de, Undated (Box 6)
      - Davis, C. K., 1899 February 19 (Box 6)
      - Day, W. R., Undated (Box 6)
      - Frye, W. P., Undated (Box 6)
      - Urriuta, V., 1906 November 3 (Box 6)
    - Senators
      - Allison, W. B., 1895 September 16 (Box 6)
      - Beveridge, A., 1908 March 23 (Box 6)
      - Conkling, Roscoe, 1879 August 21 (Box 6)
      - Cullom, S. M., 1911 January 4 (Box 6)
      - Depew, Chauncey, 1909 August 2, 1912 February 9 (Box 6)
      - Elkins, S. B., 1908 January 15 (Box 6)
      - Foraker, J. B., 1906 May 28 (Box 6)
      - Frye, W. P., 1905 October 23 (Box 6)
      - Hoar, George F., 1900 February 19 (Box 6)
      - Kean, John, 1907 February 1 (Box 6)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1906 January 26-1915 October 5 (Box 6)
      - Logan, John A., 1882 December 1 (Box 6)
      - O'Gorman, J. A., 1912 January 10 (Box 6)
      - Penrose, B., 1911 April 12 (Box 6)
      - Pinchot, G., 1906 October 13 (Box 6)
      - Scott, W. B., 1902 June 24 (Box 6)
      - Smith, W. A., 1910 June 16 (Box 6)
      - Smoot, Reed, 1921 June 17 (Box 6)
      - Spooner, John C., 1906 June 29 (Box 6)
      - Sumner, Charles, 1870 December 24 (Box 6)
  - Volume III: Correspondence with Congressmen, Judges, Navy and Army, Mayors of New York, Authors
    - Congressmen
      - Burton, Theodore E., 1908 November 23 (Box 7)
      - Calder, William M., 1911 May 24 (Box 7)
      - Cannon, J., 1908 February 15 (Box 7)
      - Clark, Champ, 1911 July 24 (Box 7)
      - Davis, John W., 1921 May 27 (Box 7)
      - Douglas, Albert, 1908 July 14 (Box 7)
      - Foss, George Edmund, 1906 March 27 (Box 7)
      - Gillett, F. H., Undated [September 21] (Box 7)
      - Glynn, Martin H., 1907 December 10 (Box 7)
      - Grosvenor, C. H., 1909 May 13 (Box 7)
      - Hewitt, A. S., 1874 November 17 (Box 7)
      - Hitt, Robert R., 1906 June 8 (Box 7)
      - Kahn, Julius, 1911 January 3 (Box 7)
      - Longworth, Nicholas, 1906 September (Box 7)
      - Mann, James R., 1908 September 21 (Box 7)
      - Phelps, W. W., 1889 March 18 (Box 7)
      - Reed, Thomas B., 1888 June 28 (Box 7)
      - Scott, Charles F., 1912 May 19 (Box 7)
    - Judges
      - Brewer, David J., 1905 September 29, 1907 October 18 (Box 7)
      - Brown, H. R., 1908 November 28 (Box 7)
      - Chase, Salmon P., 1869 August 2 (Box 7)
      - Davis, Vernon M. (to Miss Reid), 1907 July 21 (Box 7)
      - Day, William R., 1913 January 2 (Box 7)
      - Gray, George, 1909 March 1, 1913 January 9 (Box 7)
      - Harlan, John M., 1907 October 19 (Box 7)
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1907 October 27-1912 December 31 (Box 7)
      - Luston, Horace H., 1911 June 9 (Box 7)
      - Moody, W. H., 1907 July 27 (Box 7)
      - Morrow, W. W., 1912 December 16 (Box 7)
      - O'Brien, Morgan J., 1905 January 7 (Box 7)
    - Navy and Army
      - Biddle, John, Undated [November 28] (Box 7)
      - Chaffee, Adna, Undated [sep 12] (Box 7)
      - Crozier, William, 1907 July 28 (Box 7)
      - Cowles, William S., 1906 July 2, 1909 July 19 (Box 7)
      - Custer, George A., 1876 February 26 (Box 7)
      - Evans, R. D., 1906 August 23 (Box 7)
      - Ireland, W. W., 1919 January 17 (Box 7)
      - Keifer, J. Warren, 1912 June 20 (Box 7)
      - Mahan, A. T., 1899 October 20 (Box 7)
      - Miles, Nelson S., 1906 August 16, 1907 January 28 (Box 7)
      - O'Reilly, R. M., 1906 May 28 (Box 7)
      - Pershing, John J., 1918 December-1921 December 8 (Box 7)
      - Sampson, Archibald J., 1912 December 18 (Box 7)
      - Schurz, Carl, 1876 July 11 (Box 7)
      - Sherman, William T., 1879 March 12 (Box 7)
      - Sims, William S., 1910 December 6, 1923 November 30 (Box 7)
      - Watson, J. C., 1910 February 27 (Box 7)
      - Wilson, James H., 1912 December 16 (Box 7)
      - Wood, Leonard, 1914 November 16-1921 April 10 (Box 7)
      - Unidentified signature, 1883 September 13 (Box 7)
    - Mayors of New York City
      - Low, Seth, 1904 December 17 (Box 7)
      - McClellan, George, 1906 September 17, undated (Box 7)
      - Mitchell, John P., 1911 August 3 (Box 7)
    - American Authors
      - Adams, Brooks (to Mr. Wells), 1873 December 13 (Box 7)
      - Wells, Mr., 1873 December 16 (Box 7)
      - Adams, Brooks, 1912 December 4 (Box 7)
      - Adams, Charles F., Jr., 1871 February 22 (Box 7)
      - Adams, Henry, 1907 September 12, 1913 January 19 (Box 7)
      - Aldrich, Thomas B., 1880 September 16 (Box 7)
      - Bancroft, George, 1880 July 12 (Box 7)
      - Boyesen, Hjalmar, 1880 September 19 (Box 7)
      - Bryant, William C., 1876 January 3 (Box 7)
      - Carleton, Henry G., Undated [Jan2] (Box 7)
      - Clemens, Samuel L., 1907 May 28, undated [November 25] (Box 7)
      - Craigie, P. M., 1905 July 4 (Box 7)
      - Dana, Richard H., 1878 March 16 (Box 7)
      - Davis, R. H., 1888 September 24 (Box 7)
      - Faithful, Emily, 1873 February 13 (Box 7)
      - Farragut, Logan, 1910 January 4 (Box 7)
      - Field, Eugene, 1889 March 10 (Box 7)
      - Fields, James T., 1880 September 21 (Box 7)
      - Frederic, Harold, 1895 April 23 (Box 7)
      - Garland, Hamlin, Undated (Box 7)
      - Gibson, Charles, Undated [March 29] (Box 7)
      - Gregory, Eliot, undated (Box 7)
      - Griffis, Elliot, 1908 November 23 (Box 7)
      - Harte, Bret, 1870 December 30 (Box 7)
      - Hawthorne, Jullian, 1882 November 2 (Box 7)
      - Hearn, Lafcadio, Undated (Box 7)
      - Holt, Henry, 1907 October 29 (Box 7)
      - House, Edward H., 1894 August 9 (Box 7)
      - Howe, Julia W., 1905 June 16 (Box 7)
      - Howells, William D., 1898 August 12, 1906 May 7 (Box 7)
      - James, Henry, 1876 March 11 (Box 7)
      - Johnson, Rossiter, 1912 December 6 (Box 7)
      - Kellogg, Vernon, 1922 February 9 (Box 7)
      - Leland, Charles G., 1888 April 20 (Box 7)
      - Martin, Frederick T., 1912 January 14 (Box 7)
      - Miller, Alice D., Undated [September 30] (Box 7)
      - Miller, Joaquin, 1882 October 21 (Box 7)
      - Page, Thomas N., 1911 March 10 (Box 7)
      - Rhodes, James F., 1907 October 24 (Box 7)
      - Rice, Alice H., 1907 June 30 (Box 7)
      - Riley, James W., 1888 October 23 (Box 7)
      - Roe, Edward P., 1878 February 13 (Box 7)
      - Stoddard, R. H., 1871 June 13 (Box 7)
      - Story, W. W., 1890 March 10 (Box 7)
      - Taylor, Bayard, 1874 August 18 (Box 7)
      - Van Dyke, Henry, 1906 December 19 (Box 7)
      - Vincent, Edward, Undated (Box 7)
      - Wallace, Lew, 1891 November 27 (Box 7)
      - Wharton, Edith, Undated (Box 7)
      - White,Richard G., 1883 July 21 (Box 7)
      - Wheeler, Hallie E. R., Undated (Box 7)
      - Whitman, Walt, 1879 April 14 (Box 7)
      - Whittier, John G., 1885 June 5 (Box 7)
      - Woolsey, Theodore S., Undated [September 26] (Box 7)
  - Volume IV: Correspondence with Journalists, Divines, College Presidents, Bankers and Financiers, Legal, Medical, Well-Known Americans, American Women
    - American Journalists
      - Anthony, Susan B., 1870 February 8 (Box 8)
      - Bennett, J. G., 1879 February 15 (Box 8)
      - Bowen, Clarence W., 1913 April 12 (Box 8)
      - Bowles, Sam, 1870 January 20 (Box 8)
      - Childs, George W., 1875 June 11 (Box 8)
      - Church, William C., 1907 October 26 (Box 8)
      - Curtis, George William, 1869, July 9, 1871 June 5 (Box 8)
      - Dana, C. A., 1888 July 17 (Box 8)
      - Field, Kate, 1869 November 10 (Box 8)
      - Forbes, Archibald, 1880 December 13 (Box 8)
      - Fitch, George H., 1905 October 4 (Box 8)
      - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1898 July 29 (Box 8)
      - Godkin, E. L., 1872 March 25 (Box 8)
      - Greeley, Horace, 1867 December 22 (Box 8)
      - Halsted, Murat, Undated [July 14] (Box 8)
      - Hulbert, William Henry, 1877 October 10 (Box 8)
      - Johnson, Willis Fletcher, 1916 May 24 (Box 8)
      - Kohlsaat, H. H., 1905 December 7 (Box 8)
      - Marble, Manton, 1878 August 3 (Box 8)
      - Moore, J. B., 1921 May 5 (Box 8)
      - More, Paul E., 1912 June 15 (Box 8)
      - Pulitzer, Joseph, 1903 July 1 (Box 8)
      - Pulitzer, R., 1914 November 19 (Box 8)
      - Shaw, Albert, 1907 October 28 (Box 8)
      - Smalley, George W., 1883 October 10, 1906 April 20 (Box 8)
      - Townsend, George Alfred, 1912 December 21 (Box 8)
      - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1871 January 21 (Box 8)
      - Watterson, Henry, 1909 November 4, 1910 August 2 (Box 8)
      - Weed, Thurlow, 1875 August 8 (Box 8)
      - White, Horace, 1901 November 16 (Box 8)
      - Young, John Russell, 1870 (Box 8)
    - Divines
      - Abbott, Lyman, 1911 January 17 (Box 8)
      - Beecher, H. W., 1873 July 24 (Box 8)
      - Black, Hugh, 1914 July 1 (Box 8)
      - Brent, C. H., Undated (Box 8)
      - Brewster, Benjamin, 1913 December 20 (Box 8)
      - Cheshire, J. B., 1908 July 7 (Box 8)
      - Doane, W. C., 1909 feb 27 (Box 8)
      - Farley, John, 1912 December 31 (Box 8)
      - Greer, David H., 1913 January 22, 1916 October 24 (Box 8)
      - Grosvenor, William, 1916 September 19 (Box 8)
      - Leonard, W. A., 1910 February 22, May 24 (Box 8)
      - Manning, William T., 1921 April 28 (Box 8)
      - Nichols, William F., 1907 October 3, 1912 February 9 (Box 8)
    - College Presidents, etc.
      - Alderman, Edwin A., 1908 September 19 (Box 8)
      - Avery, S., 1909 May 26 (Box 8)
      - Barrows, David P., 1921 May 5 (Box 8)
      - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1905 July 17, 1906 September 25 (Box 8)
      - Coffman, L. D., 1922 January 16 (Box 8)
      - Dalmey, Charles W., 1911 June 17 (Box 8)
      - Garfield, H. A., 1912 November 27 (Box 8)
      - Hale, Edward E., 1898 November 22 (Box 8)
      - Hadley, A. T., 1906 December 26, 1908 November 21 (Box 8)
      - Hibben, J. G., 1914 January 10 (Box 8)
      - Gayley, C. M., 1921 Sep1 (Box 8)
      - Hughes, R. M., 1921 April 15 (Box 8)
      - Hyde, W. D., 1908 May 5 (Box 8)
      - James, Edward J., 1911 January 4 (Box 8)
      - Jordan, David Starr, 1907 November 2, 1908 May 23 (Box 8)
      - Judson, Harry Pratt, 1907 June 14 (Box 8)
      - Lowell, A. Lawrence, 1911 June 23 (Box 8)
      - MacCracken, Henry M., 1908 June 29 (Box 8)
      - McChesney, W. R., 1921 August 29 (Box 8)
      - McKinney, David, 1906 June 29 (Box 8)
      - Moore, J. B., 1906 October 23 (Box 8)
      - Moses, Bernard, 1910 January 10 (Box 8)
      - Peabody, Endicott, 1921 July 21 (Box 8)
      - Overstreet, H. A., 1910 February 5 (Box 8)
      - to Overstreet, H. A. (from W. R.), 1910 February 24 (Box 8)
      - Porter, Noah (To Mr. Phelps - crossed out), 1884 October 21 (Box 8)
      - White, T. R., Jr., 1884 October 25 (Box 8)
      - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1905 July 4 (Box 8)
      - Taylor, James M., 1912 December 2 (Box 8)
      - Thwing, Charles, 1912 November 30 (Box 8)
      - Van Hise, Charles R., 1910 June 6 (Box 8)
      - Wilber, B. T., 1912 November 29, undated [January 12/13] (Box 8)
      - White, Andrew A., 1908 June 19 (Box 8)
      - Wilber, R. Lyman, 1921 May 9 (Box 8)
    - Bankers, Financiers, etc.
      - Astor, John Jacob, 1889 March 20, undated (Box 8)
      - Astor, W. W., Viscount Astor, 1906 July 11 (Box 8)
      - Astor, John J., Honorable, Undated (Box 8)
      - Belmont, A., 1906 February 9 (Box 8)
      - Carnegie, Andrew, 1899 March 24-1906 August 28 (Box 8)
      - Clews, Henry, 1912 August 14 (Box 8)
      - Davison, H. P., Undated [June 12] (Box 8)
      - Duncan, W. B. (to Miss Mills), Undated (Box 8)
      - Fish, S., 1905 July 3, 1908 December 4 (Box 8)
      - Dodge, Cleveland H., 1912 November 26 (Box 8)
      - Hagin, J. B. (to Mrs. Mills), 1900 January 9 (Box 8)
      - Harriman, E. H., 1908 May 18 (Box 8)
      - Lanier, Charles (to Mrs. Mills), 1910 January 9 (Box 8)
      - Morgan, J. Pierport, 1909 June 30, undated (Box 8)
      - Rockefeller, J. D., 1911 January 5 (Box 8)
      - Vanderlip, F. A., 1908 May 25 (Box 8)
      - Villard, Henry, 1900 feb 1 (Box 8)
      - Witherbee, F. S., Undated [January 24] (Box 8)
    - Legal
      - Cadwaldar, J. L., Undated (Box 8)
      - Gerry, E. T., 1906 February 19 (Box 8)
      - Hedges, Job, 1906 December 21 (Box 8)
      - Payne, J. B., 1921 November 24 (Box 8)
      - Scott, James B., Undated [September 4] (Box 8)
      - Stetson, F. L., Undated (Box 8)
      - Woodford, S. L., 1905 June 30 (Box 8)
    - Medical
      - Abbe, Robert, 1911 January 25 (Box 8)
      - James, Walter B., 1905 February 21 (Box 8)
      - Lusk, W. B., 1921 December 9 (Box 8)
      - McCosh, A. F., Undated [September 22} (Box 8)
      - Trudeau, E. C., Undated (Box 8)
    - Famous Americans
      - Beacon, J. H., Undated (Box 8)
      - Blaine, J. G., Jr., Undated [April 1] (Box 8)
      - Bliss, R. W., Undated [June 18] (Box 8)
      - Conant, Charles A., 1910 June 14 (Box 8)
      - Dodge, Harrison H. (to Miss Boardman), 1921 June 8 (Box 8)
      - Douglass, F., 1884 August 24 (Box 8)
      - Du Chaille, P. B., 1887 November 22 (Box 8)
      - Edison, Thomas A., 1889 September 10 (Box 8)
      - Field, Cyrus W., 1869 September 13 (Box 8)
      - Gompers, Samuel, 1909 June 10 (Box 8)
      - Hammond, John Hays, Undated [December 18] (Box 8)
      - Latrobe, O., Undated [July 12] (Box 8)
      - Marquand, A., 1911 July 23 (Box 8)
      - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1912 January 15 (Box 8)
      - Stedman, E. C., 1876 February 9 (Box 8)
      - Tilden, S. J., 1894 September 30 (Box 8)
      - Warren, Whitney, Undated (Box 8)
      - Wheeler, Joseph, 1902 (Box 8)
      - Wood, James, Undated (Box 8)
    - Famous American Women
      - Carnegie, Mrs. Andrew, Undated [July 9] (Box 8)
      - Gildersleeve, Virginia C., 1921 September 26 (Box 8)
      - Logan, Mrs. John A., 1907 December 6 (Box 8)
      - Robinson, Mrs. C. Roosevelt, 1905 October 10, Undated [December 20] (Box 8)